<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
  #%L
  gw4e
  $Id:$
  $HeadURL:$
  %%
  Copyright (C) 2017 gw4e-project
  %%
  Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy
  of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"), to deal
  in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights
  to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell
  copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is
  furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:
  
  The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in
  all copies or substantial portions of the Software.
  
  THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
  IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
  FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE
  AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
  LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM,
  OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN
  THE SOFTWARE.
  #L%
  -->

<cheatsheet title="Use the  graph">
   <intro>
      <description>
         Let's do it !
      </description>
   </intro>
   
   <item title="Switch to the GW perspective" >
      <description>
      In the Package Explorer, double click the graph you've created earlier, so that the editor is displayed.<br/>  
      Switch to the GW4E perspective<br/>  
      Click the <b>Properties</b> view<br/>  
      <br/>
      You will now manipulate graph elements. Whenever you've done some update , save your work, by clicking the Save menu toolbar button.
      </description>
   </item> 
   <item title="Play with graph elements, menu and toolbar " >
      <description>
       <b>- 1-</b> In the palette click the <b>Vertex</b> element <br/>
       <b>- 2-</b> Click the <b>Vertex</b> element in the palette, move the cursor on top of the graph and click, a new <b>Vertex</b> with a default name is displayed<br/>
       <b>- 3-</b> Modify the name as you want<br/>
       <b>- 4-</b> Click <b>Edge</b> in the palette, then click the <b>Start Vertex</b>, drag your cursor until you are over any vertex, and click it<br/>
       As you can see a no link is created, because the model accepts only one edge and we already have one.  
	   <b>- 5-</b> Delete the <b>e_init</b> edge and repeat the operation.<br/>
       <b>- 6-</b> Click the newly created <b>edge</b><br/>
       <b>- 7-</b> Click the <b>red</b> cross icon in the menu toolbar, the <b>edge</b> is deleted<br/>
       <b>- 8-</b> Click the undo <b>yellow</b> icon, the <b>edge</b> is back<br/>
       <b>- 9-</b> Click the newly created <b>Vertex</b><br/>
       <b>-10-</b> Click the <b>red cross</b> icon in the menu toolbar, the <b>Vertex</b> and the <b>edge</b> are deleted<br/>
       <b>-11-</b> Click the undo <b>yellow</b> icon, the <b>vertex</b> and the <b>edge</b> are back<br/>
       <b>-12-</b> Click the created <b>Vertex</b><br/>
       <b>-13-</b> Click the <b>Copy</b> icon and then click the graph, the <b>Paste</b> icon is enabled<br/>
       <b>-14-</b> Click the <b>Paste</b> icon, the <b>Vertex</b> is duplicated<br/>
       <b>-15-</b> Right-click the graph, a popup menu appears with the <b>Undo</b>, <b>Redo</b> and <b>Delete</b> menu items we already used just above<br/>
       <b>-16-</b> Right-click the graph, and click <b>Show In</b>  <b>Package Explorer</b>, the graph file is revealed in the <b>Package Explorer</b><br/>
       <b>-17-</b> Right-click the graph, and click <b>Layout</b>. You can see many <b>Layout</b> menu options. Depending on the graph the result might be what you're looking for .. or not . This is an experimental feature.<br/>
      </description>
   </item>       
  <item title="Filtering graph elements" >
      <description>
      Whenever the graph is huge and cannot be displayed in one shot on the screen, it might be difficult to focus on particular element.  
      In this case, you can use the filters. In the Outline view, check the Filter check box. When elements are filtered, you can click on them to put the focus on the desired element.<br/>  
      <br/>
      To begin enable Filtering by checking the Filter check box. <br/>
      <b>Filtering by Name</b><br/>
      Enter a value on the name text field, the elements in the outline view table are filtered depending on the entered value. <br/>
      <b>Filtering by Description</b><br/>
      Enter a value on the description text field, the elements in the outline view table are filtered depending on the entered value. <br/>
      <b>Filtering by Blocked status</b><br/>
      Select <b>Yes</b> when you want to display Blocked element.<br/>
      Select <b>No</b> when you want to display non blocked element.<br/>
      Select <b>Empty</b> when you don't want to take into account this filter.<br/>
      <br/><br/>
      
      <b>Filtering on Vertex properties</b><br/>
      Expand the Vertex Filters section<br/>
      <b>Filtering by Requirement</b><br/>
      Enter a value on the Req text field, the elements in the outline view table are filtered depending on the entered value. <br/>
      <b>Filtering by Shared status</b><br/>
      Select <b>Yes</b> when you want to display Shared vertex<br/>
      Select <b>No</b> when you want to display simple Vertex<br/>
      Select <b>Empty</b> when you don't want to take into account this filter.<br/>      
      <b>Filtering by Init value</b><br/>
      Enter a value on the Init text field, the elements in the outline view table are filtered depending on the entered value. <br/>    
	  <br/><br/>
	  
      <b>Filtering on Edge properties</b><br/>
      Expand the Edge Filters section<br/>
      <b>Filtering by Weight</b><br/>
      Select an operator sign (upper,lower,equal,...) and enter a value, the elements in the outline view table are filtered depending on the entered value. <br/>
      <b>Filtering by Guard status</b><br/>
      Select <b>Yes</b> when you want to display Guarded edge<br/>
      Select <b>No</b> when you want to display no Guarded edge<br/>
      Select <b>Empty</b> when you don't want to take into account this filter.<br/>      
      <b>Filtering by Action status</b><br/>
      Select <b>Yes</b> when you want to display edge having script in the Action<br/>
      Select <b>No</b> when you want to display edges that dont have script in the Action<br/>
      Select <b>Empty</b> when you don't want to take into account this filter.<br/>              
      </description> 
   </item>   
   
</cheatsheet>
